A Guide to the Adaline M. Humphreys Travel Album, 1938
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Adaline M. Humphreys Travel Album, 1938
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
AV2017.1
1 album.
Humphrey, Adaline M.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift
Scope and Content
Photo album with handwritten travel narrative created by Adaline M. Humphreys for her relative, Maude B. Humphreys, to commemorate a trip they took together in November 1938 to Williamsburg and Jamestown, Virginia, on their way to visit an aunt who resided in Durham, North Carolina. The narrative describes some of the Colonial Williamsburg exhibition buildings they toured, as well as their dining experience at the Travis House restaurant. Photos document the major exhibition buildings they visited, including the Governor's Palace, Capitol, Courthouse, Powder Magazine, Raleigh Tavern, Bruton Parish Church, and Wren Building. The album also contains images of the church ruins, John Smith statue, and excavation progress on Jamestown Island, Virginia. Both Maude B. Humphreys and Adaline M. Humphreys are portrayed in candid photos taken during their ride on the Cape Charles ferry.
Arrangement
Organized in page number order.
Index Terms
Persons:
Humphreys, Adaline M.; Humphreys, Maude B.
Genre and Form Terms:
Photograph albums; Black and white photographs
Subjects:
Historic buildings - Virginia - Williamsburg
Geographical Names:
Williamsburg (Va.) - Photographs; Williamsburg (Va.) - Buildings, structures, etc.
Contents List
- 1938, A detailed watercolor and ink copy of "A Map of Tidewater" with notes detailing where important towns in Virginia and Maryland are located. (Page Hum-1)
- 1938, Photo of the side elevation of "The Oaks" in Salisbury, Maryland (Page Hum-2)
- 1938, Photo of the "Virginia Lee," the Cape Charles ferry that the photographer took from Maryland to Virginia (Page Hum-3)
- 1938, Photo of the shoreline, as seen from the "Virginia Lee" ferry (Page Hum-4)
- 1938, Photo of the front entrance of the Governor's Palace, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-5)
- 1938, Photo of the back gates surrounding the Governor's Palace garden, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-7)
- 1938, Photo of the rear elevation of the Governor's Palace (Page Hum-8)
- 1938, Photo of the Governor's Palace kitchen, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-9)
- 1938, Exterior elevation of the Public Gaol, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-10)
- 1938, Photo of the side elevation of Bruton Parish Church, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-11)
- 1938, Photo of the front elevation of the Raleigh Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-12)
- 1938, Photo of the picket fence surrounding the Raleigh Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-13)
- 1938, Photo of interior of the Raleigh Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-14)
- 1938, Photo of the interior of the Raleigh Tavern, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-15)
- 1938, Photo of a brick pathway in the boxwood garden behind the Letitia House (Page Hum-16)
- 1938, Photo of the carriage house located at the rear of the Letitia House, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-17)
- 1938, Photo of the exterior elevation of the Courthouse, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-18)
- 1938, Photo of the front elevation of the Powder Magazine, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-19)
- 1938, Photo of the exterior elevation of the Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-20)
- 1938, Photo of a green on the campus of the College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-21)
- 1938, Photo of the spire of Bruton Parish Church, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-22)
- 1938, Photo of ruins of church on Jamestown Island, Virginia (Page Hum-23)
- 1938, Photo of John Smith statue on Jamestown Island, Virginia (Page Hum-24)
- 1938, Photo of two men working on excavations on Jamestown Island, Virginia (Page Hum-25)
- 1938, Photo of Maude B. Humphreys sitting on a porch (Page Hum-26)
- Photo of Adaline M. Humphreys sitting on a porch (Page Hum-27)
- 1938, Photo of exterior elevation of Governor's Palace, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-28)
- 1938, Photo of rear elevation of Capitol, Williamsburg, Virginia (Page Hum-29)
- 1938, Photo of the front entrance of the Mason home in Durham, North Carolina (Page Hum-30)
- 1938, Portrait of the album compiler's Aunt Mary Mason surrounded by two small dogs and standing in her yard in Durham, North Carolina (Page Hum-32)
- 1938, Photo of the North Carolina sky (Page Hum-33)
- 1938, Photo of chapel at Duke University at night (Page Hum-34)